export const questions = [
  {
    question: 'The stones of Stonehenge are aligned with the ___.',
    answers: ['Solstice', 'Equinox', 'Full Moon', 'North Pole'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Between the years 185 & 1604, there were at least eight historical accounts of what astronomical event?',
    answers: [
      'Lunar Impact',
      'Supernova',
      'Total Solar Eclipse',
      'Transit Of Venus',
    ],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'In 1543, ___ proposes that the Earth travels around the Sun.',
    answers: [
      'Tycho Brahe',
      'Andreas Vesalius',
      'Leonard Fuchs',
      'Nicolaus Copernicus',
    ],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 3,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who built the first reflecting telescope in 1668?',
    answers: [
      'Johannes Kepler',
      'Galileo Galilei',
      'James Gregory',
      'Issac Newton',
    ],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 4,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In 1676, Danish astronomer Ole Roemer measured the speed of light using what planet?',
    answers: ['Mercury', 'Venus', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 5,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What German-born British composer/astronomer discovered the planet Uranus in 1781?',
    answers: [
      'Edmond Halley',
      'Charles Messier',
      'Anders Celsius',
      'William Herschel',
    ],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 6,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What was Charles Messier looking for when he created his "Messier Catalogue"?',
    answers: ['Nebulae', 'Galaxies', 'Comets', 'Globular Clusters'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 7,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What in the solar system was discovered in 1845 using mathematical predictions?',
    answers: ['Asteroid Belt', 'Oort Cloud', 'Neptune', 'Pluto'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 8,
  },
  {
    question: 'What did Albert Einstein win his only Nobel Prize for?',
    answers: [
      'The Photoelectric Effect',
      'Special Relativity',
      'General Relativity',
      'Unified Field Theory',
    ],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 9,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In 1924, ___ announces that the spiral nebula Andromeda is actually a seperate galaxy, ending the notion that the Milky Way was the only galaxy.',
    answers: ['Eugene Shoemaker', 'Jan Oort', 'Edwin Hubble', 'David Levy'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 10,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which NASA project preceded both Apollo & Gemini?',
    answers: ['Redstone', 'Agena', 'Mercury', 'Skylab'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 11,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the first American to reach space?',
    answers: ['Deke Slayton', 'John Glenn', 'Wally Schirra', 'Alan Shepard'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 12,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which Apollo mission brought humans beyond low earth orbit for the first time?',
    answers: ['Apollo 1', 'Apollo 8', 'Apollo 9', 'Apollo 10'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 13,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the flight director during the apollo 11 lunar landing?',
    answers: ['Ken Mattingly', 'Gene Kranz', 'John Young', 'Glynn Lunney'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 14,
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the command module pilot of Apollo 11?',
    answers: ['Tom Hanks', 'Michael Collins', 'Neil Armstrong', 'Buz Aldrin'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 15,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What did Neil Armstrong say next after his famous "That\'s one small step for (a) man; one giant leap for mankind" quote?',
    answers: [
      'There seems to be no difficulty in moving around.',
      'Yes, the surface is fine and powdery.',
      'The descent engine did not leave a crater of any size.',
      "We're essentially on a very level place here.",
    ],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 16,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which Apollo mission was struck by lightning shorty after launch?',
    answers: ['Apollo 12', 'Apollo 13', 'Apollo 14', 'Apollo 15'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 17,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which Apollo mission was the first to include a Lunar Rover?',
    answers: ['Apollo 15', 'Apollo 16', 'Apollo 17', 'Apollo 18'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 18,
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the last Apollo mission?',
    answers: ['Apollo 16', 'Apollo 17', 'Apollo 18', 'Apollo 19'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 19,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In 1984, Bruce McCandless completed the first untethered spacewalk by using the ___.',
    answers: ['AMU', 'ASMU', 'MMU', 'HHMU'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 20,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which country has NOT had a citizen visit the ISS?',
    answers: ['South Africa', 'United Arab Emirates', 'Malaysia', 'China'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 21,
  },
  {
    question: 'How fast does the ISS travel around the Earth?',
    answers: ['2,288 mph', '7,000 mph', '13,000 mph', '17,500 mph'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 22,
  },
  {
    question:
      'The ___ brothers are the only siblings to have both traveled in space.',
    answers: ['Hadfield', 'Kelly', 'Reisman', 'Cassidy'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 23,
  },
  {
    question: 'What ISS module provides stunning views of the Earth below?',
    answers: ['Bigelow', 'JEM', 'Cupola', 'MRM'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 24,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What country has provided the ISS with two large, external robotic arms?',
    answers: ['Switzerland', 'Germany', 'Canada', 'Italy'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 25,
  },
  {
    question: 'The ISS has had a continuous human presence since ____.',
    answers: ['2000', '2001', '2002', '2003'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 26,
  },
  {
    question: 'About how many miles above the earth does the ISS orbit?',
    answers: ['200', '250', '300', '350'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 27,
  },
  {
    question: 'What happens to urine on the ISS?',
    answers: [
      'It is discarded out into space',
      'It is used as fertilizer in botanical experiments',
      'It is stored and sent back to Earth for testing',
      'It is recycled into drinking water',
    ],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 28,
  },
  {
    question: 'What year did the Space Shuttle program conclude?',
    answers: ['2011', '2013', '2015', '2017'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 29,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In 2018, European astronaut Alexander Gerst temporarily plugged up a leak in the ISS with ___.',
    answers: ['Bubble gum', 'Trash', 'A sock', 'His finger'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 30,
  },
  {
    question: 'What planet do the Galilean moons orbit?',
    answers: ['Venus', 'Mars', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 31,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which Galilean moon is suspected to have deep liquid water oceans?',
    answers: ['Europa', 'Ganymede', 'Callisto', 'Io'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 32,
  },
  {
    question: 'What planet has a rotational axis of over 90Â°?',
    answers: ['Uranus', 'Neptune', 'Venus', 'Saturn'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 33,
  },
  {
    question: 'What spacecraft has traveled the farthest from Earth?',
    answers: ['Voyager 1', 'Voyager 2', 'New Horizons', 'Cassini'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 34,
  },
  {
    question: 'What planet has a day length nearly identical to Earth?',
    answers: ['Neptune', 'Mars', 'Venus', 'Mercury'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 35,
  },
  {
    question:
      'The "Pale Blue Dot" photograph was taken after Voyager 1 passed what planet?',
    answers: ['Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Uranus', 'Neptune'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 36,
  },
  {
    question:
      'The word planet comes from the Greek word "planetes", meaning ___.',
    answers: ['Pearl', 'Season', 'Priest', 'Wanderer'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 37,
  },
  {
    question: 'What planet hosts the small, oblong moons Phobos & Deimos?',
    answers: ['Mercury', 'Venus', 'Mars', 'Neptune'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 38,
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the first rover to rove on Mars?',
    answers: ['Spirit', 'Curiosity', 'Opportunity', 'Sojourner'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 39,
  },
  {
    question: 'What type of star is our sun?',
    answers: ['Yellow Dwarf', 'Red Giant', 'White Dwarf', 'Brown Dwarf'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 40,
  },
  {
    question: 'What NASA observatory is built into a Boeing-747?',
    answers: ['CERN', 'James Webb', 'Hubble', 'SOFIA'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 41,
  },
  {
    question: 'What US observatory detected gravitational waves in 2015?',
    answers: ['LIGO', 'AMiBA', 'CERN', 'SNOLAB'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 42,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What twin telescope array sits near the summit of Mauna Kea, Hawaii?',
    answers: [
      'Large Binocular Telescope',
      'Keck',
      'Gran Telescopio Canarias',
      'Hobby-Eberly Telescope',
    ],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 43,
  },
  {
    question: 'What will the James Webb space telescope orbit?',
    answers: ['The Moon', 'Pluto', 'Earth-Moon L2', 'Sun-Earth L2'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 44,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ___ telescope, currently under construction in Chile, will become the world's largest optical/near-infrared telescope.",
    answers: ['Supermassive', 'Extremely Large', 'Colossal', 'Herculean'],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 45,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What project plans to use a ground based laser to accelerate small probes to Alpha Centauri and beyond?',
    answers: [
      'Starlink',
      'Project Kuiper',
      'Hongyun Project',
      'Breakthrough Starshot',
    ],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 46,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What SpaceX launch vehicle currently under development, plans to bring humans to the Moon, Mars and beyond?',
    answers: ['Falcon', 'Dragon', 'Starship', 'Falcon Heavy'],
    correct: 'c',
    questionNumber: 47,
  },
  {
    question: 'What aerospace manufacturer was founded by Jeff Bezos in 2000?',
    answers: [
      'Rocket Lab',
      'Blue Origin',
      'United Launch Alliance',
      'Sierra Nevada Corporation',
    ],
    correct: 'b',
    questionNumber: 48,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What NASA mission currently in progress, aims to collect and return a sample from near-Earth asteroid Bennu?',
    answers: ['ASTER', 'InSight', 'NEOWISE', 'OSIRIS-REx'],
    correct: 'd',
    questionNumber: 49,
  },
  {
    question: 'What NASA program aims to return humans to the moon by 2024?',
    answers: ['Artemis', 'Athena', 'Hermes', 'Ersa'],
    correct: 'a',
    questionNumber: 50,
  },
];

export const answersArray = questions.map((question) => question.correct);
